Today, we're testing out GPT Image 2 for
product photography. Has OpenAI finally
solved the text label problems for AI
images? Is it the Nano Banana killer?
And why is nobody talking about its
biggest weakness? Welcome back to the
channel. And if you're new here, my name
is Thomas, and I make videos about AI
product photography. GPT Images 2
released last week, and everyone has
been calling it the Nano Banana killer,
and that graphic design has changed
forever. I have spent the last week
testing it out with different products
and different prompts to see if it's
really better than Nano Banana Pro. You
can, of course, use GPT Image 2 directly
within Chat GPT, but to get maximum
fidelity and 4K quality images, I have
been using it on Higgsfield, who were
kind enough to give me access to the
model and also sponsor this video. And
towards the end of this video, we're
going to combine GPT Image 2 with C
Dance 2 to create professional-looking
product commercials. And if you want to
do this for yourself, there's going to
be a link in the description below, but
now let's get into the examples. The
first thing I wanted to test out was the
label text rendering and how it compares
to Nano Banana Pro. And for this, we're
going to use these four products as
examples. To start out with, we're going
to create frames for an action camera
commercial with different text elements
that's then going to be animated using C
Dance 2. And if you've been watching
some of my other videos, you know I like
to start with the ending hero shot of
the commercial to then fill out the
commercial backwards so we can end up
where we want to. So, I created this as
the ending frame with a couple of
different specs that I'm then thinking
we're going to animate in individually
in different frames during the
commercial. So, for the first specs,
which was 8K 120 FPS, I wanted to create
an image where a snowboarder turns and
kind of snow blows up and the text forms
from the snow blowing up in the air. So,
I used our hero image as reference along
with this prompt, and we got this
result. And here, we run into the
biggest problem that I have noticed with
GPT Image 2. The text effect looks
really good, and at first, everything
seems fine. But on landscape images, if
we zoom in a bit, you can see that
there's this weird noise pattern in the
images that keeps on happening when I
generate something that has a landscape
environment. And it's really weird
because if we look at the other images
we generated for this action cam
commercial, some of them have absolutely
no noise pattern in them. But then
again, this one, which is underwater,
has kind of the same weird pattern in
the bubbles. So, it's some weird thing
in the model that makes it hard to do
certain patterns, especially for
environments. And just to see the
difference, I ran the exact same prompt
with Nano Banana Pro, and this was the
result. I would say the text effect is
better in GPT Image 2, but the overall
image quality is better in Nano Banana
Pro. But looking at the accuracy of the
text and the product in these images,
it's really good. I mean, even the small
power text on the side of the product is
correct. But you might be thinking, this
product doesn't even kind of have a text
label. And yes, I hear you. So, next up,
we're going to try with this whiskey
bottle. And I already know that Nano
Banana Pro will not handle the small
intricate text details on this label.
So, let's see if GPT Image 2 can handle
it. For this one, I have to say I was
really impressed with the text rendering
capabilities of GPT Image 2. It got
every single word right on the label and
didn't mess up once. Comparing the label
accuracy to the image generated by Nano
Banana Pro, we can see that Nano Banana
Pro made a lot of mistakes on the small
text on the label, while GPT Image 2
kept everything perfect. Comparing the
images side by side, not taking into
account the label accuracy errors in
Nano Banana Pro, I would say that the
image from Nano Banana Pro looks a bit
more photorealistic.
But then again, the overall design
language and also the label accuracy of
GPT Image 2 makes it the only usable
image. I wanted to make it even harder
for the models to get the label right.
So, that's why I prompted for a pouring
shot of the bottle where the label will
have to be sideways in the image. From
many painful experiences, I have also
learned that Nano Banana Pro usually
struggles with getting the label
correctly right when you turn the
product on the side inside the image.
Now, looking at this result from GPT
Image 2, it's almost flawless. There
might be the slightest weirdness going
on around the badger word on the label,
but other than that, it's perfect. And
to my surprise, Nano Banana Pro actually
got this pouring shot right as well. So,
I guess this one is a tie. Next, I
wanted to see how well it would
understand me asking for a woman
balancing a shampoo bottle on her
shoulder while running her fingers
through her hair, and if it would break
the product accuracy. It took a couple
of generations to get it just as I
wanted it, but I have to say I was
really impressed with this result.
Again, the design style of the text is
nice, and the product label is
completely accurate. I'm also impressed
how it placed the product in between her
shoulder and her hair and the
interaction between those. Comparing the
results to Nano Banana Pro, the images
are very similar, but there just seems
to be a bit more pop in the GPT 2
images. So, GPT 2 wins this one. I did
another test with this product as well,
with the bottle floating amongst bubbles
with different catchphrases related to
the shampoo. And I think you can guess
which one is GPT Image 2 and which one
is Nano Banana Pro as the story is the
same for this one. Nano Banana Pro's
result just looks more boring and dull,
while the result from GPT Image 2 just
has something about it that makes it a
better design. Next up, we're going to
use this energy drink to test out the
design and text capabilities of both
models to see which one can make a
better kind of poster design where all
the ingredients are laid out next to the
energy drink. And these were the two
results. Now, which one do you think is
better before I reveal which model made
which image? And here again, I would say
that the same thing is repeating itself.
The design language of GPT Image 2 is
slightly better. It's just more polished
and looks more professional. But the
weird pattern comes up again in the
environment and in some parts of the
liquid. So, I don't know how to call
this one. I maybe have to give it a tie.
Now, if you want to take these assets
one step further and turn them into
professional product commercials, you
can jump over to the video tab in
Higgsfield and choose C Dance 2. Now, if
you haven't seen my full tutorial of how
to turn images like this into a
professional product commercial using C
Dance, you can check it out here after
the video. But basically, all we have to
do is pick C Dance 2 from the model
drop-down menu and load in our assets
that we just created. Then, using the C
Dance 2 multi-shot prompter skill that I
created and you can download from the
description below, we're going to get a
long, complicated multi-shot prompt that
looks like this. Then, we can take that
prompt and paste it into Higgsfield, and
we're going to get commercials that
looks like this.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Overall, GPT Image 2 is extremely good
at text rendering, but it has some flaws
when it comes to more wide environment
shots and these weird noise patterns
that come up in some environments. If
you want access to all the prompts I use
in this video and all my other videos,
you can join the school community from
the link below. And if you want to make
your own product commercial using GPT
Image 2 and C Dance 2, make sure to
check out Higgsfield and the full
tutorial I made on that, but otherwise,
I'll see you in the next one.